# Giovanni Lion

# **Generative AI Engineer**

Experienced machine learning engineer, with specific focus on generative AI. Proficient in multiple platforms, languages, and embedded systems. Experienced with the latest LLMs and diffusion models. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

### Contact

giovanni.lion@gmail.com https://giovannilion.link +852 66859017 Hong Kong

## **Skills**

**★★★★★** Python

\*\*\*\* Docker

**★★★★★** Linux

**★★★★☆** LLMs

**★★★★☆** LDMs

★★★★☆ Git

**★★★★☆** Node.js

★★★★ MongoDB

★★★☆☆ Agile

# **Experience**

**PART-TIME VISITING LECTURER** THE HONG KONG POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY, SCHOOL OF DESIGN, HONG KONG

September 2019 – Present

- Published scholarly papers on the topic of generative Al, resulting in invitations to present at international conferences.
- Conducted quantitative and qualitative research by delivering workshops to students and professionals and evaluating their use of generative AI tools.
- Developed a real-time TensorRT accelerated img2img pipeline using webrtc, StableDiffusion and docker: https://github.com/venetanii/videosd
- Lectured in MSc elective courses Sound Design, Interactive Multimedia Environment and Transformative Technologies.
- Coordinated and facilitated group projects, teaching students how to work together and communicate effectively.

**PROJECT ASSOCIATE** THE HONG KONG POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY, SCHOOL OF DESIGN, HONG KONG

September 2017 – July 2019

- Collaborated with school staff to develop and implement extracurricular activities and workshops to support student learning.
- Developed a 32-speaker ambisonics system capable of realtime spatialization of audio content.

- Developed and taught specialized lectures in the field of computer science and maker education, resulting in higher student engagement and improved learning outcomes.
- Collaborated with other teachers to develop interdisciplinary projects that integrated computer science topics with other subjects.

#### **ROBOT OPERATOR** HANSON ROBOTICS, HONG KONG

December 2017 – July 2019

- Responsible for overseeing performance scripting, transportation, setup, and operation of Sophia, the worldrenowned humanoid robot.
- Gained in depth knowledge of ROS (Robot operative system), and its computer vision and chat-bot components.
- Worked on high-profile events, including a commercial shoot with Cristiano Ronaldo and World Investment Forum 2018 at UN in Geneva.

# IT MANAGER AMBULATORIO SAN MASSIMO, PADOVA (ITA - REMOTE)

September 2018 – Dec 2022

- Lead the design and implementation of the network architecture and services (database, VoIP, appointment booking API) of a medical clinic with two sites.
- Automated backup and routine system administration tasks using docker to reduce manual effort.
- Streamlined and automated system administration tasks, resulting in a 60% reduction in operational costs.

# FOUNDER CEO AND LEAD PROGRAMMER HAGAO STUDIO, HONG KONG

September 2014 – December 2015

- Oversaw all aspects of mobile game development and management as team leader.
- Created Featherman, an innovative game aimed at raising awareness about migratory birds' environmental issues.
- Partnered with WWF Mai Po Reservoir.

# FOUNDER CEO AND LEAD PROGRAMMER 83BITS, HONG KONG

September 2011 – September 2014

- Successfully established and managed the primary product, AllIn1Social, a web application for managing content and advertising campaigns on Facebook pages.
- Developed front-end and back-end development using Ruby on Rails and MongoDB.
- Worked with Facebook Advertising API and map-reduce tasks to provide marketing campaign analytics.

#### FOUNDER CEO SHI CHENG TRADING, HONG KONG

December 2009 - Present

• Established and led Shi Cheng Trading Limited, a successful import company specializing in innovative gel material and

- foam pillows and mattresses for the Hong Kong and China markets.
- Managed the end-to-end operations of the company, including procurement, sales, logistics, and customer service, to ensure smooth and efficient business processes.
- Oversaw the company's Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) system, utilizing OpenERP (now Odoo) and currently ERPNext, to maintain accurate records of sales, purchases, stock, and accounting.

#### **SOCIAL MEDIA SPECIALIST 77AGENCY, MILAN**

September 2008 – September 2011

- Responsible for developing and deploying Facebook applications for marketing purposes.
- Worked with influential Italian companies including Lavazza, Repubblica, RCA, CondèNast, and Mondadori.

## **Education**

# THE HONG KONG POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF DESIGN, HONG KONG

Ph.D.

September 2019 – Present

- Awaiting to defend a PhD thesis titled "Concept formation in computational creativity" addressing the last 4 years of evolution of generative AI.
- Conducted research and utilized techniques such as VAEs, GANs, GPT-4 and real-time diffusion pipelines.
- Managed a Discord server and generative AI Discord bots for research purposes.

# THE HONG KONG POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF DESIGN, HONG KONG

MSc in Multimedia Entertainment Technology September 2014 – August 2015

- Developed a mobile game for Android, iOS and Windows Phone utilizing cocos2dx-is.
- Continued project after graduation by funding a company.

#### UNIVERSITÀ COMMERCIALE L. BOCCONI, MILAN

MSc in Organization and IT Systems September 2005 – December 2007

• Graduated magna cum laude

#### UNIVERSITÀ COMMERCIALE L. BOCCONI, MILAN

BSc in International Markets and New Technologies January 2002 – August 2005